- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[tropical music]
[热带音乐]
♪ ♪
[calming music]
[平静的音乐]
- Greetings,
children of Bikini Bottom.
- 问候，
比基尼泳裤的孩子们。
I am Karen,
the computer fairy.
我是凯伦，
电脑仙子。
[singing opera]
【唱戏】
And I have a magical
tale to tell.
而我有一个神奇的
故事要讲。
Once upon a time,
there was a dim-witted sea star
曾几何时，
有一颗愚笨的海星
who was about to stuff
his fat face.
谁正要塞东西
他那张肥胖的脸。
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
♪ ♪
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
That idiot has such a huge
pile of patties.
那个白痴竟然有这么大的力气
一堆肉饼。
I don't think he'll notice
if one walks away.
我认为他不会注意到
如果一个人走开。
[laughs]
[笑]
- [chomping]
- [咀嚼]
Aww, I need more ketchup.
哇，我需要更多番茄酱。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- Hmm, which patty to choose?
- 嗯，选择哪个肉饼？
This one?
Nope, too small.
这个？
不行，太小了。
This one?
Nope, been chewed.
这个？
不，被嚼烂了。
This one?
Nope, the seeds are missing.
这个？
不，种子不见了。
Hmm.
唔。
[groans]
[呻吟]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- [groans]
Stand up, you moron!
- [呻吟]
站起来，你这个白痴！
- [shouting]
- [喊叫]
- Get me an ice pack,
you idiot!
- 给我一个冰袋，
你这个白痴！
- Where are you, voice?
Where are you?
- 你在哪里，声音？
你在哪里？
- Uh, Patrick?
- [shouts]
- 呃，帕特里克？
- [喊叫]
Oh, it's you, SpongeBob.
哦，是你，海绵宝宝。
I thought you were this crazy
voice that keeps telling me
我以为你这么疯狂
不断告诉我的声音
what to do.
该怎么办。
- Oh, that's probably
your conscience.
-哦，这可能是
你的良心。
- What are "conscience"?
Are they bad?
- 什么是“良心”？
他们坏吗？
- No, a conscience is a tiny
voice inside you
- 不，良心很小
你内心的声音
that tells you the difference
between something that's right
这告诉你区别
在正确的事情之间
and something--
- [groans]
还有一些东西——
- [呻吟]
- That's wrong.
- Hmm.
- 那是错误的。
- 唔。
So I should do what the voice
tells me to do?
所以我应该做那个声音
告诉我做什么？
- Now that's a smart little
sea star.
- 现在这是一个聪明的小家伙
海星。
- [laughs]
- [笑]
[chewing]
[咀嚼]
- [chuckles]
- [轻笑]
- [slurping]
- [发出声音]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
Patrick, this is your
conscience speaking.
帕特里克，这是你的
良心说话。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
Oh, nice to meet you,
conscience.
哦，很高兴认识你，
良心。
- So stupid.
- 太蠢了。
So, stupid, the first thing
you need to do is buy some more
所以，笨蛋，第一件事
你需要做的就是多买一些
Krabby Patties on the double.
Hi-ya, hey-o!
双份蟹蟹肉饼。
嗨呀，嘿哦！
- That'll be the first thing
I do, conscience.
- 这将是第一件事
我愿意，良心。
- Yes!
- 是的！
- Right after
I run some errands.
- 就在之后
我办一些事。
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
[groans]
- Huh?
[呻吟]
- 啊？
No!
[grunts]
不！
[咕哝]
I'm calling the shots here.
Now get that Krabby Patty.
我在这里发号施令。
现在去拿蟹肉饼吧。
- It's just a little list!
Please, conscience?
- 这只是一个小清单！
请问，良心吗？
- All right, pea brain.
Make it quick.
- 好吧，豌豆脑。
快点吧。
- Number one:
high-five everyone!
- 第一：
大家高五！
Huh!
- No, put me down first!
哈！
- 不，先把我放下！
Ow!
- High five!
噢！
- 高五！
High five!
- [screams]
高五！
- [尖叫]
- Low five!
- [screams]
- 低五！
- [尖叫]
- High five!
- [groans]
- 高五！
- [呻吟]
- High five!
- [screams]
- 高五！
- [尖叫]
- High five!
- Ow!
- 高五！
- 噢！
- High five!
- [groans]
- 高五！
- [呻吟]
- High five!
- Ow!
- 高五！
- 噢！
[moaning]
[呻吟]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
[ragtime piano music]
[拉格泰姆钢琴曲]
♪ ♪
Number two:
Ice cream!
第二：
冰淇淋！
Yeah!
[waggles tongue]
是的！
[摇摆舌头]
One Double Chocolate
Molar Blowout, please.
一份双份巧克力
臼齿喷发，请。
- One Molar Blowout,
coming up!
- 一颗磨牙爆裂，
来了！
- No! You hate ice cream.
You only want Krabby Patties.
- 不！你讨厌冰淇淋。
你只想要蟹肉饼。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Hey, you!
Cancel that order!
嘿，你！
取消该订单！
[groans]
[呻吟]
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
- [grunts]
- [shouts]
- [咕哝]
- [喊叫]
Ow!
噢！
You hate high fives
and ice cream?
你讨厌击掌
还有冰淇淋？
Are you sure
you're my conscience?
你确定吗
你是我的良心吗？
- Uh, uh, I, uh--I'm absolutely
positively your conscience.
- 呃，呃，我，呃——我绝对
积极地你的良心。
♪ ♪
- Hey, doesn't your nose grow
when you tell lies
- 嘿，你的鼻子没长吗
当你说谎时
in fairy tales?
- Nope.
童话故事里？
- 没有。
Noses only grow when
you make up the truth.
鼻子只有在以下情况下才会生长
你编造了事实。
- Ooh.
- See?
- 哦。
- 看？
- [laughs]
I wanna make up the truth too!
- [笑]
我也想编造真相！
Uh, I ate a hot air balloon
for breakfast.
呃，我吃了一个热气球
早餐。
Mm.
I-I mean, um...
毫米。
我-我是说，嗯...
I did not eat a hot air balloon
for breakfast.
我没有吃热气球
早餐。
Hey, I got a big nose too!
Nose fight!
嘿嘿，我也有一个大鼻子！
鼻子大战！
En garde!
- [screaming]
准备好了！
- [尖叫]
[grunts]
- Hey!
[咕哝]
- 嘿！
[both grunting]
[cheering]
[两人都咕哝着]
[欢呼]
- Hooray!
[cheering]
- 万岁！
[欢呼]
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
- [shouting]
- [喊叫]
all: Uh-oh.
全体：呃哦。
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
♪ ♪
both: Sorry.
两人：抱歉。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[both shouting and groaning]
[尖叫和呻吟]
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
- Time to let your conscience
be your guide.
- 是时候让你的良心
成为你的向导。
Give me that list!
把那个清单给我！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[mutters]
[嘀咕]
Here.
- Hey, only one errand left.
这里。
- 嘿，只剩下一项任务了。
Gotta give a Plankton
a Krabby Patty!
必须给一个浮游生物
蟹肉饼！
- ♪ Oh, yeah! ♪
- ♪ 哦，是的！ ♪
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
- Wonder why I wanted to give
Plankton a patty?
- 想知道为什么我想给予
浮游生物是肉饼吗？
- Why not Plankton?
He's a sweetheart.
- 为什么不是浮游生物？
他是个甜心。
Huh?
[grunts]
啊？
[咕哝]
And as your conscience,
I demand you toss that patty
作为你的良心，
我要求你扔掉那块肉饼
in the mail slot!
在邮件槽中！
- Ooh, I love mail slot toss!
- 哦，我喜欢投掷邮件槽！
Hmm!
唔！
- Not so hard!
Hmm?
- 没那么难！
唔？
Mm!
毫米！
- I've been wanting to hit
the beach all week.
-我一直想打
整个星期都在海滩。
[laughs]
all: Goo Lagoon!
[笑]
所有人：古泻湖！
Goo Lagoon!
- Huh?
古泻湖！
- 啊？
[groans]
Huh?
[呻吟]
啊？
Ah!
啊!
Patrick, please promptly pursue
Plankton's patty.
帕特里克，请速追
浮游生物的肉饼。
Get the idea?
明白了吗？
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
[groans]
[呻吟]
- [moaning]
- [呻吟]
How many planktons does it take
to change a light bulb?
需要多少浮游生物
换灯泡？
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
One.
一。
- Oh, now I get the idea!
- 哦，现在我明白了！
♪ Ooh, gotta follow
that patty! ♪
♪ 哦，必须跟随
那个小馅饼！ ♪
- [screams]
Ouch!
- [尖叫]
哎哟！
Wait for me,
you pink pinhead!
等我，
你这个粉红色的小傻瓜！
[groans]
[呻吟]
[surf rock music]
[冲浪摇滚音乐]
- Mmm.
- 嗯。
- Ow.
- Ow!
- 噢。
- 噢！
Hey, watch it!
嘿，注意看！
- Ow!
- [burps]
- 噢！
- [打嗝]
Huh?
啊？
- [spitting]
- [随地吐痰]
- [spits]
- [吐口水]
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
- There's blubber mouth.
- 有一张鲸脂嘴。
♪ ♪
[gulps]
[吞咽]
- There's Plankton's patty!
- 这是 Plankton 的肉饼！
- You know what to do.
- Do I?
- 你知道该怎么做。
- 我是吗？
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Oh, yeah!
- [groans]
哦，是啊！
- [呻吟]
[grunts]
[shouting]
[咕哝]
[喊叫]
Huh?
[shouting]
啊？
[喊叫]
Whoa!
[groans]
哇！
[呻吟]
[moans]
Oh, well.
[呻吟声]
哦，好吧。
No patty for Plankton.
[cries]
浮游生物没有肉饼。
[哭声]
- [grunts]
I'm going in!
- [咕哝]
我要进去了！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Ugh, just being near
a whale's mouth
- 呃，只是靠近而已
鲸鱼的嘴
gives me the creeps.
- [grunts]
让我毛骨悚然。
- [咕哝]
- [shouts]
- [喊叫]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- Quiet, you fool!
You'll wake up Pearl.
- 安静，你这个傻瓜！
你会叫醒珀尔的。
- [screams quietly]
- [小声尖叫]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- [gulps]
[snores]
- [吞咽]
[打鼾]
- [groans]
This is snug.
- [呻吟]
这很舒服。
- Mother always said I'd end up
in a whale's belly.
- 妈妈总是说我会结束
在鲸鱼的肚子里。
Or prison.
- Hey, who-a goes-a there?
或者监狱。
- 嘿，谁去那里？
- Who goes where?
- The name's a-Geppetto.
- 谁去哪里？
- 名字是a-Geppetto。
Take off your hats.
Stay a while.
摘下你的帽子。
停留一会儿。
- We don't have time
for a visit, old man.
- 我们没有时间
来拜访一下，老人。
We're just trying to find
our sandwich!
我们只是想找到
我们的三明治！
- Sandwich?
- 三明治？
No, I haven't seen
anything like that
不，我还没见过
类似的事情
around here in months.
[chuckles]
几个月后就到这里了。
[笑声]
Huh?
[chuckles]
啊？
[笑声]
- Hey, Geppetto,
what's that behind your back?
- 嘿，杰佩托，
你背后那是什么？
- Is that our Krabby Patty?
- Nope.
- 那是我们的蟹黄饼吗？
- 没有。
Oh!
[grunts]
哦！
[咕哝]
- [grunts]
Aha!
- [咕哝]
啊哈！
I got the patty!
- Aha!
我拿到了肉饼！
- 啊哈！
I got the wig!
我拿到假发了！
- Son, they're-a stealing
our food-a!
- 儿子，他们是偷东西
我们的食物-a！
- Who's stealing our food, Pop?
- 谁在偷我们的食物，爸爸？
Let me at 'em, let me at 'em!
让我对付他们，让我对付他们！
- Get him, Pinocchio!
- 抓住他，匹诺曹！
[all grunting]
[全都咕哝]
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
[all grunting]
[全都咕哝]
- Oh, no.
A stomachache at the beach?
- 哦，不。
去海边肚子疼？
That's no fun.
I wish it would go away.
那没什么好玩的。
我希望它会消失。
Hmm?
- Your wish is granted.
唔？
- 你的愿望实现了。
Hold out your hand.
伸出你的手。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- Wow!
What is this?
- 哇！
这是什么？
- For fast relief
of indigestion,
- 快速缓解
消化不良，
try Gush and Flush and wash
your pain down the drain.
尝试喷水、冲水和清洗
你的痛苦付之东流。
And my stupid husband,
while you're at it.
还有我愚蠢的丈夫，
当你在做的时候。
- [gulps]
Ah.
- [吞咽]
啊。
[groans]
[呻吟]
[all shouting]
[大家大喊]
[groans]
[呻吟]
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
- Thank you,
extra-strength Gush and Flush!
超强力喷涌和冲洗！
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
- Pinocchio, we're-a free-a!
♪ Yeah! ♪
- 匹诺曹，我们是自由人！
♪ 是啊！ ♪
- [snarls]
- [咆哮]
- Huh?
[giggles]
- 啊？
[咯咯笑]
Don't worry about the patty,
Patrick.
不用担心肉饼的问题
帕特里克.
I'll take it
to Plankton myself,
我会接受的
对浮游生物本人来说，
like a good little conscience.
See you.
就像一个善良的小良心。
再见。
[giggles]
[grunts]
[咯咯笑]
[咕哝]
- Oh, hey, Patrick.
- [grunts]
- 哦，嘿，帕特里克。
- [咕哝]
My conscience?
- You are?
我的良心？
- 你是？
- Yep, I'm Patrick's
conscience.
- 是的，我是帕特里克的
良心。
But I overslept.
但我睡过头了。
- Well, if you're my
conscience, Conscience,
- 好吧，如果你是我的
良心，良心，
then who's that?
- It's a bug!
那么那是谁呢？
- 这是一个错误！
Step on it!
- [groaning]
踩它！
- [呻吟]
- And they all lived
happily ever after.
- 他们都活着
从此幸福快乐。
So until next time,
this is--
所以直到下一次，
这是——
- Karen!
- The computer fairy,
- 凯伦！
- 电脑仙子，
hoping all your dreams
come true.
希望你所有的梦想
成真。
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
- Let me at 'em, Pop.
Let me at 'em.
- 让我来对付他们吧，爸爸。
让我来对付他们。
Let me at 'em, let me--
aww!
让我对付他们，让我——
哇！
[swashbuckling music]
[虚张声势的音乐]
♪ ♪
[accordion music]
[手风琴音乐]
♪ ♪
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
You people are proof that
evolution can go in reverse!
你们就是证明
进化可以逆转！
all: [shushing]
全体：[嘘]
- [humming "Entrance
of the Gladiators"]
- [哼哼“入口
角斗士”]
♪ ♪
Pew! Pew! Pew!
座位！座位！座位！
all: [oohing]
全体：[噢]
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
♪ Ta-da! ♪
♪ 哒哒！ ♪
[cheers and applause]
[欢呼和掌声]
- Mr. Squidward,
why aren't these walking
- 章鱼哥先生
为什么这些人不走路
wallets spending money?
- [grunts]
钱包花钱？
- [咕哝]
Because they're too busy
watching SpongeBob cook.
因为他们太忙了
看海绵宝宝做饭。
- What?
- Ow!
- 什么？
- 噢！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- [whistling]
- [吹口哨]
- Well, he's not exactly
maximerizing his work time
- 嗯，他不完全是
最大限度地利用他的工作时间
with those flourishes.
与那些繁荣。
But boy, does that boyo
have talent.
但是男孩，那个男孩吗？
有才华。
[cheerful noises]
[欢快的声音]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
And talent is worth money.
人才是值钱的。
[shouting]
[all scream]
[喊叫]
[所有人尖叫]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- [singing]
- [唱歌]
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
[confused noises]
I have X-ray vision!
[混乱的声音]
我有X光视力！
I can see through walls.
我可以透过墙壁看到。
- Calm your waters, lad.
I just knocked it down.
- 冷静点，小伙子。
我刚刚把它打倒了。
- I--why'd you do that?
- 我--你为什么这么做？
- In the restaurant business,
it's called an open kitchen,
- 在餐饮业，
这就是所谓的开放式厨房，
so the customers can watch
the cook cook.
这样顾客就可以观看
厨师做饭。
- Oh, Mr. Krabs,
I don't know if I can take
-哦，蟹老板先生，
我不知道我是否可以接受
that kind of pressure.
- Nonsense.
那种压力。
- 废话。
You're a born performer.
Ooh.
你是一个天生的表演者。
哦。
Here.
[grunts and spits]
这里。
[咕哝和吐口水]
[marker squeaking]
[标记吱吱作响]
You've even got
your own dressing room.
你甚至还拥有
你自己的更衣室。
Huh? Huh? Huh?
啊？啊？啊？
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[shouts]
- [moans]
[喊叫]
- [呻吟]
[groans]
Come on, boyo, it's showtime.
[呻吟]
来吧，男孩，表演时间到了。
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
- [groans]
I can't.
- [呻吟]
我不能。
I've got stage fright.
我怯场了。
- SpongeBob, if you don't
come out, you're fired.
- 海绵宝宝，如果你不这样做
出来吧，你被解雇了。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- There he is!
- [grunts]
- 他在那儿！
- [咕哝]
- Chef Bob!
- 厨师鲍勃！
Me little star!
我的小星星！
Break a leg.
Break two legs.
打断一条腿。
打断两条腿。
- My leg!
- Shut up, Fred.
- 我的腿！
- 闭嘴，弗雷德。
[singing]
[歌唱]
[cheers and applause]
[欢呼和掌声]
all: [oohing]
全体：[噢]
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
[all groaning]
[全都呻吟]
- What?
- 什么？
- [giggles nervously]
- [紧张地咯咯笑]
- That's just wrong!
- 那是错误的！
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
- Come on, boyo,
razzle-dazzle them!
- 来吧，男孩，
让他们眼花缭乱！
- [groans]
- Huh?
- [呻吟]
- 啊？
- Oh, what do I do?
What do I do?
- 哦，我该怎么办？
我该怎么办？
Huh?
Oh.
啊？
哦。
♪ ♪
- [groans]
Hmm?
- [呻吟]
嗯？
♪ ♪
[cheering]
[欢呼]
- Hi, everybody!
Who's hungry?
- 大家好！
谁饿了？
[all groaning]
[全都呻吟]
- I guess I am.
- 我想我是。
- Welcome, welcome to my job
in the kitchen of Chef Bob.
- 欢迎，欢迎来到我的工作岗位
在鲍勃厨师的厨房里。
I cook and dance,
I wear square pants,
我一边做饭一边跳舞
我穿的是四角裤
cooking for this hungry mob.
为这群饥饿的暴民做饭。
♪ Your order, please! ♪
♪ 请您下单！ ♪
[cheering]
[欢呼]
- The little Chef Bob
is a sensation.
- 小厨师鲍勃
是一种感觉。
[showy music]
[华丽的音乐]
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
[murmuring]
[淙淙]
- Hi, everybody!
Who's hungry?
- 大家好！
谁饿了？
all: We are!
全体：我们是！
- Yay!
[goofy noises]
- 耶！
[愚蠢的声音]
[cheering]
[欢呼]
Yah!
啊！
- [laughing]
- [笑]
- Ah!
Huh? Huh?
- 啊！
啊？啊？
[goofy noises]
- [elated screaming]
[愚蠢的声音]
- [兴高采烈的尖叫]
- Voila!
- 瞧！
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
♪ Ta-da! ♪
♪ 哒哒！ ♪
[watch beeping]
- Oh, look at the time.
[注意蜂鸣声]
- 哦，看看时间。
I gotta get home
and get my beauty sleep.
我得回家了
睡个美容觉。
- Oh, what died
on that guy's neck?
- 哦，死了什么
在那家伙的脖子上？
Oh, it's his head.
- Huh?
哦，这是他的头。
- 啊？
Hey, what died on your neck?
Oh, it's your head.
嘿，你脖子上死了什么？
哦，这是你的头。
[all laughing]
[全都笑了]
- Why, that little plagiarist.
That was my line!
- 哎呀，那个小抄袭者。
那是我的台词！
- [laughs]
- [笑]
Obviously the sleep
hasn't been helping!
明显是睡觉
一直没有帮忙！
[laughs]
[笑]
- Did-did I say that?
I didn't say that.
- 我有说过吗？
我没那么说。
- [laughs]
Hey, do me.
- [笑]
嘿，做我吧。
Insult me.
- All right.
侮辱我。
- 好的。
Roses are red,
violets are blue,
玫瑰是红色的，
紫罗兰是蓝色的，
I was born pretty,
what happened to you?
我生来就漂亮
你怎么了？
- [laughs]
That was a good one.
- [笑]
那是一件好事。
- Huh?
Whoa!
- 啊？
哇！
- Chef Bob, we don't speak
like that to our customers.
- 鲍勃厨师，我们不说话
就像对我们的客户那样。
- Me next!
Shoot me a zinger!
- 下一个是我！
给我开一枪！
- Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't get that.
- 哦，对不起。
我没明白。
I don't speak goober!
我不会说脏话！
[all laughing]
[全都笑了]
- I love it.
Guilty as charged.
- 我喜欢它。
被指控有罪。
[laughs]
[笑]
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
[cheering]
[欢呼]
- Oh, great.
I've created a monster.
- 哦，太好了。
我创造了一个怪物。
A funny, talented monster.
一个有趣、才华横溢的怪物。
- [laughing]
- [笑]
Oh, I gotta hand it to you.
哦，我得把它交给你。
That new insult comedy act is
really bringing in the money.
新的侮辱喜剧是
真正带来了钱。
- Hmm.
- 唔。
- Ah, what's this here?
- Sorry, Mr. Krabs.
- 啊，这是什么？
- 对不起，蟹老板。
It's a list of things Chef Bob
needs for his dressing room.
这是厨师鲍勃的清单
需要他的更衣室。
- Oh, does he?
- 哦，是吗？
Fresh-cut seaweed,
鲜切海带，
a manicurist for SpongeBob's
puppet hand--What?
海绵宝宝的美甲师
傀儡手——什么？
A bigger dressing room?
更大的更衣室？
- In the meantime, we'll just
take over your office,
- 与此同时，我们将
接管你的办公室，
blubber boy.
- Blubber boy?
鲸脂男孩。
- 哭哭啼啼的男孩？
Huh?
Oh.
啊？
哦。
No way!
[grunting]
决不！
[咕噜声]
[groans]
- What's the matter, Krabs?
[呻吟]
- 怎么了，蟹蟹？
You don't like money?
- [groans]
你不喜欢钱？
- [呻吟]
- What?
Of course I like money.
- 什么？
我当然喜欢钱。
The office will be ready
in five minutes.
办公室将准备就绪
五分钟后。
- Chef Bob, I think your
insults are mean and hurtful.
- 鲍勃厨师，我想你的
侮辱是卑鄙且有害的。
What do you say we just go back
to the Krabby Patty routines,
你说怎么样我们就回去吧
蟹肉饼的做法，
huh?
- Need I remind you that
嗯？
- 需要我提醒你吗
my insults pay your salary?
我的侮辱可以支付你的工资吗？
- Yes, sir.
I mean, no, sir.
- 是的，先生。
我的意思是，不，先生。
- Chef Bob, you stole my line.
- 鲍勃厨师，你抢了我的台词。
I do all the insults
around here.
所有的侮辱都是我做的
在这附近。
- Oh, I am so sorry, Squidward.
- 哦，我很抱歉，章鱼哥。
You're absolutely right.
你是绝对正确的。
- Um, oh, well, uh, thank you.
- 嗯，哦，好吧，呃，谢谢。
It's-it's-it's really
not such a big deal.
这这这这真是
没什么大不了的。
- Let me make it up to you.
Hi, everybody!
- 让我来补偿你。
大家好！
I'd like to introduce you
to a very good friend of mine.
我想向您介绍一下
给我的一个很好的朋友。
Squidward Tentacles!
[cheers and applause]
章鱼哥的触手！
[欢呼和掌声]
- Huh?
Oh, no, please, please.
- 啊？
哦，不，求你了，求你了。
You're-you're too kind.
你、你太善良了。
- I was gonna ask Squidward
how old he was,
-我本来想问章鱼哥
他几岁了，
but then I remembered
he can't count that high.
但后来我想起来了
他不能算那么高。
- Huh?
- 啊？
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Hmm?
[growls]
- 唔？
[咆哮]
All right, that's it!
好吧，就是这样！
You can't talk to Squidward
that way!
你不能和章鱼哥说话
那样！
He is one of my best friends.
他是我最好的朋友之一。
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
- That's even more insulting.
——那就更侮辱人了。
- Get a load of him, folks!
- 伙计们，让他来吧！
He must've been born on a
highway because that's where
他一定是出生在
高速公路，因为那是哪里
most accidents happen.
Yeah!
大多数事故都会发生。
是的！
[clucking]
[laughter]
[咯咯笑]
[笑声]
- [shouting]
- [喊叫]
- Ow!
- Not funny!
- 噢！
- 不好笑！
[both shouting]
[两人大喊]
[laughter]
[笑声]
- [shouting]
- [喊叫]
- He scores!
- 他得分了！
[chattering]
[喋喋不休]
- Have a drink!
- [gasping]
- 喝一杯！
- [喘气]
[gargling]
[漱口]
- No, no!
[shouting]
- 不，不！
[喊叫]
[all oohing]
[全都欢呼]
[rumbling]
[隆隆声]
[both shouting]
[两人大喊]
[exciting music]
[激动人心的音乐]
- En garde!
- 准备好了！
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
[groaning]
[呻吟]
- [laughing]
- [笑]
[both groaning]
[两人都呻吟]
[all gasping]
[全都喘气]
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
[both crying]
[两人都哭了]
Oh! Ah! Ugh!
哦！啊!啊!
[all muttering]
[大家嘀咕]
- Me customers!
- 我的顾客！
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- All right, enough of this.
- 好吧，够了。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Chef Bob,
you are hereby fired!
厨师鲍勃，
你特此被解雇！
Mr. Squidward,
will you do the honors?
章鱼哥先生，
你愿意吗？
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
- Let me help you slip into
something more comfortable.
- 让我帮你滑进去
更舒服的东西。
Like the gutter.
就像阴沟一样。
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
♪ ♪
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
I learned a very valuable
lesson today.
我学到了非常宝贵的知识
今天的课。
- To always be yourself
and not hide behind a puppet?
- 永远做你自己
而不是躲在傀儡后面？
- Well, yeah, that, but mostly
don't slam your puppet hand
- 嗯，是的，但主要是这样
不要猛击你的木偶手
in a register drawer.
在收银机抽屉里。
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
- [laughing]
- [笑]
Ow.
噢。
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
both: What is it,
Mr. Squidward?
两者：这是什么，
章鱼哥先生？
- It's-it's alive!
- 它 - 它还活着！
- And now it's time for...
- 现在是时候了...
"The Chef Bob
Cooking with Insults Show"!
“厨师鲍勃.
侮辱烹饪秀”！
And here's your host,
Chef Bob!
这是你的主人，
厨师鲍勃！
- Hi, everybody!
Who's hungry?
- 大家好！
谁饿了？
[cheers and applause]
[欢呼和掌声]
All right, roses are red,
violets are blue.
好吧，玫瑰是红色的，
紫罗兰是蓝色的。
I was born pretty,
what happened to you?
我生来就漂亮
你怎么了？
[cheers and applause]
[欢呼和掌声]
- Yay, yeah!
- 是啊，是啊！
[all groaning]
[全都呻吟]
[tropical music]
[热带音乐]
♪ ♪